[{"question":"<p><strong>An autobiography is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A novel written about another novelist","A true account of a novelist's life by himself","A novel in which the novelist draws mainly on materials from his own life","A novel using pronoun"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Plot in prose fiction is best defined as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The cause and \u2014 effect sequence of events","The brief summary of events",".The central event","The subject \u2014 matter of a novel"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these is not true about unity of action in a novel?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Action may be unified through a single main character","Action may be unified by being set in one place","Action may be unified by many characters",".Action may be unified by having one consistent point of view"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Action in a novel is best defined as:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The summary of the novel\u2019s story","What the characters do or say in the novel","The numerous sub \u2014 plots of the novel put together",".The totality of all the episodes in a novel leading to the conclusion"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Suspense in a novel means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The postponement of the hero<span>'<\/span>s death till the last possible moment","The intense emotions that the author conveys","The inconclusive end of a novel","When we are curious about what happens next in a"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Theme is best defined as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The subject matter of a novel or play","Central idea in a play or novel","The point of view in that novel",".The sum \u2014 total of all the characters experiences"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>What figure of speech does the following quotation contain?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Life&rsquo;s but a walking shadow (Macbeth)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A metaphor","An image","A synecdoche","An allusion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is most true about poetry?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The meaning of words are more important than their sounds","The sounds of words are more important than their meanings","The sound of words are often more important than their meanings","Sounds and meanings of words are of little consequence"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these best define exposition in drama?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The author<span>&#39;<\/span>s own general introduction to the play","The author<span>&#39;<\/span>s early exposure of his dramatist personae to conflict","Introduction to the characters and the general problem with which the play deals","The first performance of the play on stage"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When the speaker in a poem cannot be identified with the poet, that speaker is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A persona","A dramatist persona","A soliloquist","Aventriloquist"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these definitions best describes a lyric?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A short poem","A short poem in which the poet himself is speaking","A poem expressing a personal idea, feeling or mood","A poem divided into stanzas"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Among rocks, I am the loose one, among arrows, I am&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>the heart among daughters, I am the recluse, among&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>sons, the one who dies young <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What kind of repetition is used in the extract?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Anaphora","Single word repetition","Line repetition","Phrase repetition"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Apart from emphasis, what other effect does the repetition have?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Makes the poem rhythmical","Makes the poem tedious","Makes the poem monotonous","Makes the poem exhilarating"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following line from poem Western wind, when will thou blow? Is an example of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rhetorical question","Caesura","Alliteration","Nature imagery"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Identify the odd one out of these types of imagery<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Visual imagery","Tactile imagery","Synaesthesia","Literal imagery"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a poet uses mainly soft vowel sounds in a poem, the texture of the poem is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mellifluous","Harsh","Assonantal","Neutral"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sounds in the following lines may be described as an example of: The moan of doves in immemorial elms, and murmuring of innumerable bees<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alliteration","Euphony","Cacophony","A mixture of all above"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The man dies in all who keeps silent in the face of tyranny\u201d. This statement can be described as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Metaphoric","Literal","Tragic","A simile"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The literary technique in which a reader is taken to the past of a current action is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rewinding","Fast forward","Flashback","Repetition"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"}]